### **Muhammad Abdul Karim**

Brook Lane Birmingham, West Midlands B13 OBT (+44) 0750 1634 676

mohammed.a.karim98@gmail.com

# **Statement**

I am a motivated and confident individual with a strong commitment to maintaining security and ensuring the well-being of guests. My experience as a volunteer security team member has equipped me with the skills necessary to handle difficult situations and make reasoned decisions under pressure. Can Start immediately and can-do night shifts.

## **Education**

Bachelor of Science (BSc) in Networks and Cyber Security University of Sunderland, Sunderland, United Kingdom 2019 - 2022

# **Experience**

# **Seg Line**

Sunderland, United Kingdom

2020 - 2021

- Actively participated in segregation roles during football events, ensuring the separation between HOME and AWAY crowds.
- Collaborated with other volunteers and security personnel to maintain a safe and orderly environment during matches.
- Developed strong interpersonal and conflict resolution skills by handling potential disputes between fans.

#### **Volunteer Security Team Member**

Murdoch University Dubai, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

2017 - 2018

I worked a few security related roles while studying at Murdoch University Dubai.

 Volunteered as a security team member during various university events, ensuring the safety of attendees and maintaining a secure environment.

#### **Volunteer Events Security**

Al Ain, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

2015 - 2016

Worked as a volunteer events security with the government of United Arab Emirates.

Volunteered for local events held by the government, access control and crowd management.

## **Skills**

- Strong interpersonal and communication skills.
- Conflict resolution and problem-solving abilities.
- Reliable and committed to duty and responsibility.
- Impeccable personal presentation and appearance.

# Certifications

SIA Door Supervisor License